

3936 50A Street Red Deer, Alberta

□ (587) 879-4626 |
tkuipers123@gmail.com |
tkuipers |
tyler-kuipers

Technologies

00P Git HTML/JS Python

TDD Linux/Bash **Data Structures/Algorithms Docker**

Skills_

Collaboration Successfully interacted with colleagues to complete assigned tasks and projects.

Leadership Performed lead developer duties on several projects; each delivered on time without major post-launch defects.

Proficient Developer Continuously performed above the expectations of employers.

Organization Collaborated with Product Owners to prioritize user stories within projects, and consequently, deadlines were met. Communication Worked remotely for 6 months and maintained a high level of communication with colleagues and superiors.

Work Experience _

Alberta Motor Association Edmonton, Alberta

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Jun 2018 - Present

I work as a Software Developer for AMA's Insurance Division, doing development on its core insurance product.

- Daily work is completed in Gosu (a JVM language) on the Guidewire framework.
- · Daily tasks are completed using TDD methodology.
- Performs Scrum Master role on projects that are delivered on time and budget with no critical defects post-launch.
- Design and program the test framework that is currently used to run our integration tests. Changes made contributed to a 30% drop in defects on subsequent projects.
- · Planning and implementing the solutions used for online payment on AMA's website, utilizing third-party API's and Guidewire.
- · Lead transition from SVN to Git.
- Created a Docker image for use with our instance of Guidewire.
- · Hosts training sessions around TDD, unit tests, and the methodology behind them for coworkers.
- Primarily advancing skills in Gosu, Guidewire, Git, Ant, Docker, and some in Java.

Pleasant Solutions Edmonton, Alberta

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER Jan 2018 - Jun 2018

I worked as a full-stack developer on projects highly customized to the client's needs.

- Daily work was completed in C# .NET, heavily utilizing an MVC design pattern.
 - Gained experience in leadership roles for small projects.
 - TDD methodologies were used to complete tasks.
 - Front-end work was completed in a mix of C# and HTML/JS using C# Razor.
 - Primarily advanced skills in the Windows C# toolchain, XAML, HTML, JS, Git, Moq, and the NUnit Framework.

Lockheed Martin Canada Halifax, Nova Scotia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER ASSOCIATE Jan 2017 - Jan 2018

Worked as an associate software engineer developing software to be used in CMS 330.

- · Contributed to the implementation of a Data Fusion module for use with Combat Management Systems.
- · Worked with a team to develop software modules responsible for the management and status of various underwater sensors.
- · Worked in an Agile SCRUM environment.
- · Completed daily work using TDD methodologies.
- · Primarily advanced skills in Java, Git, SQL, Bash, Junit, and Java Mocking Frameworks.

Tyler Kuipers · Resume JUNE 18, 2020

The King's University

Edmonton, Alberta

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER/RESEARCH ASSISTANT

May 2014 - Sep 2016

Worked as a full stack developer; designed and implemented an approach to dynamically reference items both spatially and temporally.

- Designed and built a website that researchers could input information into; viewers could see the data and explore it.
- Researched the method utilized and authored an undergraduate thesis documenting my contribution to the Edmonton River Atlas Website
- Primarily advanced skills in PHP, HTML, JavaScript and jQuery, PostgreSQL, and PostGIS.

Education

The King's University

Edmonton, Alberta

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Sep 2012 - Dec 2016

Cousera Online

SCRUMMASTER COURSE Jan 2019 - Jan 2019